‫All right, guys.
‫So we're going to start our first project and it's going to be a small hotel website called Hotel BT
‫or BT.
‫And we're going to be using everything that we've learned up to this point.
‫So everything from the HTML and the CSS sandbox, I'm not going to throw in any extra technologies like
‫the grid system or or media queries to make it responsive.
‫I only want to deal with stuff we've already learned.
‫Once we learn that other stuff, then we'll build projects using that other stuff.
‫So if any of you guys are more experienced and you're saying, Oh, why didn't you use CSS grid for
‫this?
‫Because we haven't learned that yet.
‫Okay.
‫Now notice there are some background images in this project.
‫There will be in this lecture in the downloads, a zip file called Image Resources.
‫And it's going to have all the the images that are included in this project.
‫And where I usually get my images is pexels.com p e x else dot com and there's tons of free really,
‫really high quality stock images.
‫So what I did is I just searched for hotel and I found my images here.
‫And if you click on one, you can download different sizes.
‫So it's a, it's a great resource, it's completely free.
‫And the photos are just as high quality as, as premium photos are.
‫So let's take a look at the project.
‫So up top, we have a navigation bar, we have a logo, we're just using an H one here.
‫But you could easily use an image if you wanted.
‫We have a home about contact with a background hover effect and whatever the current page is is also
‫going to have the background.
‫Then we have a showcase area with a background image.
‫Now this background image, I did open up in Photoshop and I faded it a little bit just so that the
‫text was more readable.
‫Now you can do this with just CSS, but we haven't gone over that yet.
‫So that's something we'll do in another project.
‫But for now we're just going to use the faded out image.
‫So we have some text on this.
‫We have a link formatted as a button.
‫Then down here we have some floated boxes, we have an image, we have some text here and then here
‫we have three boxes with some icons.
‫Now we haven't gone over icons yet, and the way that we're using these is with a third party service
‫called Font Awesome, which is really awesome and it's very popular.
‫It's used all the time and basically all we have to do is include their stylesheet, their CSS, and
‫we can just add classes to elements and we can get these cool looking icons and we can actually resize
‫them with certain classes and so on.
‫All right, so we'll do that.
‫And then we have a simple footer with a copyright.
‫And then on the about page we have some text, we have an image rounded with border radius, and then
‫we have a background image with some testimonials where we float the images and the text.
‫And then on the contact page we have a form that we're going to style and then some icons down here
‫with location, phone number and address.
‫Now, as I've said before, you can't have a contact form work with just HTML.
‫You need to have some kind of server side language like PHP or something like that, which is beyond
‫the scope of this course.
‫Now at the end of this course, I may include a video or a reference to a video where you can I'll show
‫you how to use a PHP script or something like that to submit a contact form.
‫But just just know that the submission of a form is out of the scope of this course.
‫So those are the three pages that will be creating.
‫Now it's this site is not completely responsive.
‫You'll see if I go down really small, I mean, it looks okay as far as the menu and this here, this
‫even looks okay.
‫This should actually be stacked and not in three rows.
‫I think they're too narrow, but we're not going to do that just yet.
‫We may do it later on when we get into media queries and stuff like this doesn't really look very good.
‫Contact page.
‫Contact page looks okay.
‫Again, these should be stacked, but we'll get into that later on.
‫I don't want to start to do things that we haven't talked about yet.
‫So that's it, guys.
‫Let's get started with the project.